Prateek Gupta

Student

| \searrow | prat.gupta@mail.utoronto.ca | J | +1 (416) 823-4495 |
|------------|-----------------------------------|-----|-------------------|
| in | https://www.linkedin.com/in/gupra | ıt/ | guprat.github.io |

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY -

Blends lab management experience with academic training at the University of Toronto to offer solid skills in technical experiments and research activities. Incorporates a background in student recruitment outreach and tutoring to provide employers with proven organization, communications, social intelligence and strategic thinking expertise.

EXPERIENCE -

PHYSICS TUTOR

Sep 2019 - Apr 2020 | Environmental and Physical Sciences Students' Association, Univeristy of Toronto Scarborough , Toronto, Canada

Assisted and mentored students in first-year physics with course content and helped them understand difficult concepts in a very simple manner. Committed to regular weekly shifts via a drop-in style tutoring service.

INTERNATIONAL STUDENT AMBASSADOR

Jan 2020 - Apr 2020 | Office of Admissions and Student Recruitment, Univerity of Toronto Scarborough , Toronto, Canada

Assisted the Office of Admissions and Student Recruitment in their outreach to applicants around the world. Acted as a friendly mentor that helps bridge the knowledge gap between expectations and reality when it comes to studying at U of T Scarborough.

EDUCATION –

ALL INDIA SENIOR SECONDARY SCHOOL CERTIFICATE

Central Board of Secondary Education , New Delhi, India | Graduated in 2018

90+ in Math and Physics

HONOURS BACHELORS OF SCIENCE, PHYSICS AND ASTROPHYSICS SPECIALIST

University of Toronto , Toronto, Canada | 3.93 GPA

Dean's List for 2018-2019

PROJECTS

DISTRIANALYSIS

Created a Python Package named distrianalysis, that lets you input data and analyze the Gaussian or Binomial distributions arising from said data. It is available on PyPi.

SKILLS -

PYTHON C++ MYSQL INNOVATIVE AND SKILLED IN CREATIVE AND STRATEGIC THINKING
STRONG COMMUNICATION SKILLS ABILITY TO WORK COLLABORATIVELY SOLID WORK ETHIC